[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133977b", "question": "Where is the film Predator set?", "answer": "South American jungle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e05", "question": "What show debuted on September 7, 1979, with George Grande anchoring?", "answer": "SportsCenter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c0", "question": "What are female elephants called?", "answer": "Cows", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e959fe83fe1f2a824be4", "question": "Who was the first person to be awarded two Nobel prizes?", "answer": "Marie Curie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59029fb8cad1ec93f27df763", "question": "Who was Strongbow cider named after?", "answer": "Richard de Clare", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc0bfec223966ae8f885f", "question": "Charlie Brown's father was a what?", "answer": "Barber", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51be6ff04d658268c9312", "question": "Who was the husband of the female Judge Deborah in the Bible?", "answer": "Lapidoth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7361aeec85e375820b259", "question": "Where did Dr. Samuel Mudd serve prison after he was convicted for his involvement in President Lincoln's assassination?", "answer": "Fort Jefferson in the Dry Tortugas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0afcae662d71a53650fc3", "question": "Who is Fridwulfa the mother of?", "answer": "Rubeus Hagrid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe735abeec85e375820b24f", "question": "Who said, \"If you have ten thousand regulations you destroy all respect for the law.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ffb", "question": "Who was the son of Saturn and Ops, and the husband of Juno?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c36", "question": "What year saw the end of the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "2004", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133954b", "question": "Who starred as David in the TV show \"The Hogan Family\"?", "answer": "Jason Bateman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a061", "question": "Who sang \"I Want My MTV\" on the Dire Straits song \"Money For Nothing\"?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cd40b9e685cf15b733e988a", "question": "In which county in the United Kingdom is the Glastonbury Festival held?", "answer": "Somerset", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a62a32ebb971c1417fb91", "question": "What fish was the subject of a dispute between Spain and Canada from 1994 to 1996?", "answer": "Turbot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133913a", "question": "What is the full name of the fictional character Doc Savage?", "answer": "Clark Savage, Jr.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a767", "question": "In which US state is Gettysburg National Military Park?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e53", "question": "What literary work inspired Green Day's \"Who Wrote Holden Caufield\" song?", "answer": "The Catcher in the Rye", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe13266e39efa6330e0feda", "question": "Where was windsurfing invented?", "answer": "USA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c418", "question": "What name is given to the closest star to the Earth?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b285", "question": "What position was first held by Steve Allen?", "answer": "Tonight Show host", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a494", "question": "Which country's capital city lies on the River Aar?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f167cdf7c52aae91cc07be", "question": "The Bijagos Archipelago lie off which country's mainland?", "answer": "Guinea-Bissau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cafb", "question": "The fear of punishment is known as what?", "answer": "Poinephobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f0", "question": "What US state has been governed by James Polk and Austin Peay?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339253", "question": "What rocker's song \"Rock Is Dead\" is heard in the movie \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Marilyn Manson's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339216", "question": "What fictional Kansas town is the earthly home of the young Superman?", "answer": "Smallville", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b7b", "question": "In what Tom Cruise movie does his character play a doctor?", "answer": "Eyes Wide Shut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec22f68dc25ca9e12ef62b", "question": "As whom was J\u00e1n Ludv\u00edk Hyman Binyamin Hoch better known?", "answer": "Robert Maxwell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339680", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who is also known as \"The Listen Lady\"?", "answer": "Marge Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec85bdec223966ae8f8808", "question": "In the music world, who is the \"Godfather Of Grime\"?", "answer": "Wiley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015dfd6fe83fe1f2a824b81", "question": "Who wrote the first algorithm intended to be carried out by a machine?", "answer": "Ada Lovelace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59049ae8cf93664eb104869b", "question": "Marvel Comics was acquired by which major media and entertainment company in 2009?", "answer": "The Walt Disney Company", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace5", "question": "Which Greek goddess gave her name to the city of Athens?", "answer": "Athena", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d81", "question": "Whose paintings include \"The Red Room\", \"The Green Stripe\", \"The Blue Nudes\" and \"The Yellow Odalisque\"?", "answer": "Henri Matisse's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b25", "question": "In which museum does the Mona Lisa hang?", "answer": "The Louvre", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d98", "question": "What longtime London Symphony Orchestra conductor is also Woody Allen's father-in-law?", "answer": "Andre Previn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c6", "question": "The Great Gazoo was an alien in which cartoon series?", "answer": "The Flintstones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aced", "question": "Who was Jimmy Carter's vice president?", "answer": "Walter (Fritz) Mondale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23e", "question": "Which studio album did Elton John release in 1971?", "answer": "Madman Across the Water", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb5057e83c707845b211e", "question": "What is Mars' atmosphere mostly made of?", "answer": "Carbon dioxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb1f", "question": "What two-sport athlete didn't speak in his early 1990's Nike commercials because of his bad stutter?", "answer": "Bo Jackson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfa93cf3977a46e7ce447", "question": "The Statue of Liberty was a gift resulting from the diplomatic relationship between the United States and what country?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b720", "question": "In the Twelve Days of Christmas what did my true love send to me on the fourth day?", "answer": "Four calling birds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c112", "question": "What country was figure skater Elvis Stojko born in?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a936", "question": "What is the only nation that shares a land border with Monaco?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cea", "question": "What singer took his stage name from a Dublin hearing aid billboard?", "answer": "Bono", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f3058515aa2bc17b61b2ad6", "question": "Who wrote the operas \"The Magic Flute\" and \"The Marriage of Figaro\"?", "answer": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b058e662d71a53650fc6", "question": "Which museum owns the only Da Vinci painting in the Western Hemisphere?", "answer": "National Art Gallery (U.S.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa1", "question": "What is the fear of the color purple called?", "answer": "Porphyrophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a885", "question": "Mount Suribachi is the highest point where?", "answer": "Iwo Jima", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae956c574a5ce6b56b8255", "question": "What animals does a hippophobe fear?", "answer": "Horses", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ed", "question": "Which grandmaster did Bobby Fischer defeat in 1972 and became the first American to win the world chess title?", "answer": "Boris Spassky", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea4638ff048f679a45aba0", "question": "The Planting Moon is found in which month?", "answer": "May", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52f", "question": "What plant is rum made from?", "answer": "Sugar cane", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b36e121c3f17ccc40c8e08", "question": "What common household object appears in the opening scene of the film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "A light bulb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6b", "question": "Who played the role of TV's C. J. Barnes?", "answer": "David Spade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe903d901dd7bf43be5e871", "question": "Which U.S. federal agency provides protection for the federal judiciary?", "answer": "United States Marshals Service", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ead", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"The Score\"?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa95e73838c5c8a417f44", "question": "What is Podobromhidrosis?", "answer": "Bad smelling odor from sweat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60121a8a63c99d48cd169b03", "question": "What is the longest English word with only one vowel?", "answer": "Strengths", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05e", "question": "\"I melt with you\" was which band's signature hit released on their \"After the Snow\"?", "answer": "Modern English", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae68", "question": "Who were known by GI's in World War II as \"Hit & Muss\"?", "answer": "Hitler and Mussolini", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590721e13745b36be73039fb", "question": "Which Disney character is named after Ebenezer from Charles Dickens\u2019 novel \"A Christmas Carol\"?", "answer": "Scrooge McDuck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b76b01dd7bf43be5e7e4", "question": "What did the Colgate company originally sell?", "answer": "Soap and candles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cacf877e98cb97778a0c", "question": "Which Arab country houses the Rub Al-Khali or Empty Quarter, the largest continuous sand desert in the world?", "answer": "Saudi Arabia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c525", "question": "Durian fruit is banned from certain public places in South East Asia because of its what?", "answer": "Smell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b59", "question": "In Greek mythology, how many labours were imposed on Hercules?", "answer": "12", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924a", "question": "What was the title of Eddie Murphy's first movie?", "answer": "48 Hrs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93a", "question": "What hometown of Scott Joplin and Ross Perot is named for the three states whose border it sits near?", "answer": "Texarkana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f7c501dd7bf43be5e839", "question": "Algophobia or algiophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Pain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a98120565ad31a57c805", "question": "Who founded the University of Virginia?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339762", "question": "In what movie does an office worker's hypnotherapy go wrong?", "answer": "Office Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad03", "question": "What archaeological site is known as the Lost City of the Incas?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "591c3805815febcc896f9278", "question": "What is the seventh sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Libra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071fa83745b36be73039ec", "question": "What does the abbreviation of Dana's police team, RCAT, stand for in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Revitalized Citizen Arbitration Team", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600244634be4723ccac221a2", "question": "What is the movement in architecture in which buildings have an organic, amoeba-shaped form?", "answer": "Blobism\u00a0or\u00a0blobitecture\u00a0is a type of wavy, curvy building design without traditional edges or traditional symmetric form.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa5d", "question": "How was the country of Belize known prior to 1973?", "answer": "British Honduras", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a4", "question": "When did Sid Vicious join the Sex Pistols?", "answer": "1977", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecdb5fec223966ae8f88f4", "question": "What movie marked the Hollywood film debut of William Shatner?", "answer": "\"The Brothers Karamazov\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398de", "question": "What TV series detective was played by Peter Falk?", "answer": "Columbo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ee", "question": "Which river forms part of the border between England & Scotland?", "answer": "River Tweed", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c51", "question": "Who defected from a Leningrad ballet troupe in 1961?", "answer": "Rudolf Nureyev", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e5", "question": "The Caribbean island of Aruba is part of what European kingdom?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c316", "question": "What is one of pi's rational approximations?", "answer": "22/7", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abaa", "question": "What is the state capital of New York?", "answer": "Albany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac9b", "question": "Who was prime minister of the United Kingdom from 1997 to 2007?", "answer": "Tony Blair", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2594031a458464a93c46b", "question": "How many years are in a \"score\"?", "answer": "Twenty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1db", "question": "In the 1954 film \"A Star Is Born\" who played the leading man?", "answer": "James Mason", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ffb133a3a814d89068c61", "question": "The US made \"Medium Tank, M4\" is better known as what?", "answer": "The Sherman tank", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c44f", "question": "What is the main constituent of an eggshell?", "answer": "Calcium carbonate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f95b05555722f97b22684dc", "question": "Who was the Hogwarts' headmaster right before Dumbledore?", "answer": "Armando Dippet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a264", "question": "On what TV show did Alanis Morrisette appear in the 1980's?", "answer": "You Can't Do that On Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cdc", "question": "What literary character's parents were murdered in Godric's Hollow?", "answer": "Harry Potter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd664a5a5bfecdd737e0857", "question": "How many people survived the Titanic sinking?", "answer": "706", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee9", "question": "What is the technical difference between rowing and sculling?", "answer": "Rowing means using a single oar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c947", "question": "Copper gets its name from which Mediterranean country?", "answer": "Cyprus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf9e", "question": "Bill Gates dropped out of which of educational institution?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65e611f3c0ead6880d62b", "question": "According to the Bible, which Apostle was a tentmaker?", "answer": "Paul", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef59326ce05a3942286e02", "question": "In the film \"The Shawshank Redemption,\" Andy had four pin-ups of famous actresses.  Which one did he not hang on his cell wall?", "answer": "Jayne Mansfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b559e662d71a53650ff8", "question": "In Jane Austen's \"Pride and Prejudice,\" what is Mr. Darcy's first name?", "answer": "Fitzwilliam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339732", "question": "How many hard-boiled eggs does Paul Newman's character eat in \"Cool Hand Luke\"?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5f4", "question": "Which US state is known as the \u201cLand of Enchantment\u201d?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa9316ce05a3942286edd", "question": "What was the name of Good & Plenty's classic engineer mascot?", "answer": "Jerry Rice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f565d333a95c66dc4fe75b", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"The Turn of the Screw\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Britten", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e6", "question": "What year was carbon 14 first discovered?", "answer": "1940", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a14", "question": "Where does Spanish rain fall, according to \"My Fair Lady\"?", "answer": "On the plain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ce6800302c3cfae5c79b718", "question": "How many states and territories in Australia?", "answer": "6 states 10 territories", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a4", "question": "Which is the most densely populated country in the world?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce3", "question": "What fashion brand was founded by artist Gwen Stefani?", "answer": "L.A.M.B.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afef", "question": "President William McKinley was a member of what political party?", "answer": "Republican Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff6673052a821ff76ae8afc", "question": "How much did Judas Iscariot receive for betraying Jesus Christ?", "answer": "\"30 pieces of silver\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ba", "question": "What country is the \"land of the lions\"?", "answer": "Singapore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c14c", "question": "How is Samuel Langhorne Clemens better known?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa42b5c73aa70ea0b70b14", "question": "Fort-de-France is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Martinique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339760", "question": "How much of the population has survived by 2035 in Twelve Monkeys? 1, 5 or 10 percent?", "answer": "1 percent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb9", "question": "What is Lepidopterology the study of?", "answer": "Moths and butterflies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf8a", "question": "A statue of Billy Bremner stands outside the ground of which football stadium?", "answer": "Leeds United", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe64154ae7e414034b5aeab", "question": "What was the name of the Chicago hotel in which Al Capone stayed from 1928 to 1931?", "answer": "Lexington Hotel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a090", "question": "What was John Wayne's real name?", "answer": "Marion Morrison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca9d", "question": "Na is the chemical symbol for which element?", "answer": "Sodium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffcfed09dc5ec6cd98a832c", "question": "What writer had more than 70 different pen names?", "answer": "Lauran Bosworth Paine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5af25bdfb63e5727cf5a485d", "question": "What year did Cher release the single \"Believe\"?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b55c", "question": "Depending on the story, which two fruits are often considered the Queen of Fruits?", "answer": "Mangos and Mangosteens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f25", "question": "What comedy hit was produced under the working title \"East Great Falls High\"?", "answer": "American Pie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbc950a60f0007efaba0e5f", "question": "In Telltale's Season 1 of the \"The Walking Dead\" game series, what is the name of the main character?", "answer": "Lee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c6e9877e98cb977789c4", "question": "Where can you find the Dragon Blood Tree", "answer": "Yemen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fbaee2c0738315b1fb74e32", "question": "Who are Quagmire\u2019s daughters in the TV show \"Family Guy\"", "answer": "Anna Lee and Courtney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339867", "question": "In Disney's \"Dumbo\", what is it that Dumbo is made fun of for?", "answer": "His large ears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a301", "question": "Randy Poffo, who was a pitchman for Slim Jim, was better known by what name?", "answer": "\"Macho Man\" Randy Savage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ef", "question": "What year did the Queen Elizabeth II reign start?", "answer": "1952", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ec", "question": "What causes the holes in Swiss cheese?", "answer": "Bacteria", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062bbdc9d816e292245c24", "question": "Who is credited as the designer of the many statues which decorated the Parthenon?", "answer": "Phidias", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fedd8cb6ce05a3942286d74", "question": "Which NBA player has had a tattoo of the late Malcolm X on his left calf at least since 2012?", "answer": "Derrick Rose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927f", "question": "In seasons 12 and 13 of the TV show \"Big Brother\", what competitor is associated with \"crybernating\"?", "answer": "Rachel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339603", "question": "What movie coined the phrase \"In space, no one can hear you scream\"?", "answer": "Alien", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974d", "question": "What is Alecia Moore better known as?", "answer": "P!NK", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b443", "question": "Who was Joseph Merrick better known as?", "answer": "Elephant Man", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339236", "question": "What is the real first name of rock star Prince?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a068", "question": "What group was Ringo Starr with before the Beatles?", "answer": "Rory Storm and the Hurricanes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f6e7fe83fe1f2a824c1e", "question": "After his crucifixion, who takes down the body of Jesus Christ off the cross of Calvary?", "answer": "Joseph of Arimathea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7ca1ff048f679a45abf8", "question": "What do you call a group of giraffes?", "answer": "A tower", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b99c", "question": "Completed in 1911, what dam was built across the Salt River near Phoenix?", "answer": "Roosevelt Dam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4aa", "question": "Which country were the 1948 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a474", "question": "Chicago borders which of the five Great Lakes?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91c", "question": "This protein makes the blood red in color?", "answer": "Hemoglobin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59523d84736d4be723796b43", "question": "For what period of time is the Governor General of Canada appointed?", "answer": "Unfixed", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339439", "question": "Who directed the 2009 movie \"Watchmen\"?", "answer": "Zack Snyder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f5664733a95c66dc4fe761", "question": "In which film did Orson Welles play the role of Harry Lime?", "answer": "The Third Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8fc6b01dd7bf43be5e85a", "question": "The cooking spray PAM stands for what?", "answer": "Product of Arthur Meyerhoff", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c295", "question": "How many colors are there in the spectrum?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5971ddf989261e916c8e09a0", "question": "Which character from The Simpsons tries to kill Bart Simpson on many occasions?", "answer": "Sideshow Bob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339807", "question": "What nationality are the members of the 80's pop band \"A-ha\"?", "answer": "Norwegian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339830", "question": "What movie, directed by the Coen brothers, won an Oscar for \"Best Picture\" in 2008?", "answer": "No Country for Old Men", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338945", "question": "Which great painter's nickname translated literally to \"The Greek\"?", "answer": "El Greco", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f2b", "question": "Which band member of The Blues Brothers died of drug overdose?", "answer": "John Belushi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b0", "question": "Most of Transylvania is now part of what modern-day country?", "answer": "Romania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d5", "question": "In 1991, who finally broke Bob Beamon's decades-old long jump record?", "answer": "Mike Powell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d9f", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Buchanan?", "answer": "F. Scott Fitzgerald", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ec26208dc25ca9e12ef647", "question": "Which country traditionally gives London's Trafalgar Square its Christmas tree?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e2f", "question": "Who devised the Trojan Horse and led the men hidden inside it?", "answer": "Odysseus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c913", "question": "The amount of what substance in granite determines its color?", "answer": "Feldspar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010cb0d0775fa611bce6802", "question": "The last leader of the Soviet Union, Mikhail Gorbachev, was in what restaurant commercial?", "answer": "Pizza Hut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59bb29c1c9bff04efae6d759", "question": "Whose novels include \"The Joy Luck Club\" and \"The Kitchen God's Wife\"?", "answer": "Amy Tan's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa9", "question": "What CBS reality show gets its name from a term in George Orwell's novel \"1984\"?", "answer": "Big Brother", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133923b", "question": "What is the nickname of Andy's prison buddy in \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a434", "question": "Which tribes are native to New Zealand?", "answer": "Maori", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff510e2d24dd593ee3eacc7", "question": "What military campaign is colloquially known as the \"Bekaa Valley Turkey Shoot\"?", "answer": "Code-named\u00a0Operation Mole Cricket 19, Israeli aircraft destroyed 82-86 of 100 Syrian aircraft in the 1982 Lebanon War.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febaa5e7e83c707845b20de", "question": "A scientist at which company invented the pH scale?", "answer": "Carlsberg", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c9", "question": "Until 1790, what was known as Jenkins Hill?", "answer": "Capitol Hill", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd68", "question": "On what Jewish holiday is the \"Kol Nidre\" prayer recited?", "answer": "Yom Kippur", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6008dc1ef4f3bc4a292f861a", "question": "Where did Martin Luther King, Jr. give his famous \"I have a dream\" speech?", "answer": "The Lincoln Memorial (He had previously spoken to 30,000 people in 1957. This time, 250,000 people were present.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a40", "question": "In 2000, the Black Crowes released a live album recorded with what legendary guitar player?", "answer": "Jimmy Page", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c5d49076251badbead2", "question": "What year gave birth to the word \"motel\"?", "answer": "The term \"motel\" originated with the\u00a0Milestone Mo-Tel, which was constructed in 1925 by Arthur Heineman.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ad", "question": "Who played the teenage prostitute in the 1976 film \"Taxi Driver\"?", "answer": "Jodie Foster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a647", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Colorado?", "answer": "Denver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb8", "question": "Who wrote King George V Christmas speech that was broadcast in 1932?", "answer": "Rudyard Kipling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f14", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Willem Defoe and James Caviezel?", "answer": "Jesus Christ", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5902a033cad1ec93f27df768", "question": "What is typically added to Vietnamese iced coffee to sweeten it?", "answer": "Sweetened condensed milk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba09", "question": "Who won 7 gold medals in swimming at the 1972 Summer Olympics in Munich?", "answer": "Mark Spitz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c0", "question": "What did Pieter van Musschenbroek create at a namesake Dutch university in 1746 by lining a glass jar with silver foil?", "answer": "The Leyden jar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d077c9870e6f05ba600867", "question": "What film starred Drew Barrymore, Mary-Louise Parker, and Matthew McConaughey?", "answer": "Boys on the Side", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b8", "question": "To protest an unpopular tax, which US state's residents held the \"Whiskey Rebellion\" in 1794?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339228", "question": "What is \"Shawshank\" in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A prison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bacd", "question": "Who was the number 1 \u00adranked female tennis player in the world 7 out of 9 years between 1988 and 1996?", "answer": "Steffi Graf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e16", "question": "At the end of \"The Da Vinci Code\", the Holy Grail is revealed to be buried at what popular spot?", "answer": "The Louvre Museum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6aac820565ad31a57c821", "question": "Who was the most decorated American soldier during World War II?", "answer": "Audie L Murphy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388fd", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was warned that the cow was in the corn?", "answer": "Little Boy Blue", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e8a8962404ad935a7e1a63f", "question": "Which Premier League team's mascot is the Red Devil?", "answer": "Manchester United", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ae", "question": "Who signed off his radio show by saying \"Keep your feet on the ground and keep reaching for the stars\"?", "answer": "Casey Kasem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f5", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Iceland?", "answer": "Gyrfalcon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59523da6736d4be723796b45", "question": "What was the last Province or Territory that joined Canada?", "answer": "Nunavut", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e4", "question": "What was the last name of Eddie Murphy\u2019s character in the movie \u201cTrading Places\u201d?", "answer": "Valentine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ad", "question": "In what city would you find Griffith Park?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc82eec223966ae8f888f", "question": "Which professional sport in the United States commonly has multiple games on Christmas Day?", "answer": "NBA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c4e", "question": "What popular detective did Robert Downey Jr. portray in a series of movies?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16b40f7c52aae91cc07e5", "question": "What is the name of the apartment complex the Jetsons live in?", "answer": "Skypad Apartments", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b501", "question": "What is another term for a badminton bird?", "answer": "Shuttlecock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a515", "question": "Africa's Victoria Falls are on which river?", "answer": "Zambezi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0fc", "question": "Which US President served the shortest term in office?", "answer": "William Henry Harrison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf31", "question": "What event occurs at Walthamstow Stadium?", "answer": "Greyhound Racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feb34ab7e83c707845b20cc", "question": "Banknote collectors call it \"banana money\", after its artwork. Which country issued it in some of the territories that it oc\u00adcupied during World War II?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76e", "question": "\"Old Scratch\" is a nickname for whom?", "answer": "Satan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b98a", "question": "Which former heavyweight champion was nicknamed the \"Brockton blockbuster\"?", "answer": "Rocky Marciano", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a38", "question": "The \"Tuesday Club Murders\" was a novel written by what mystery writer?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a9", "question": "What are the four main levels of India's caste system?", "answer": "Brahman, Kshatriyas, Vaisyas, Sudras", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fe", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman goddess Venus?", "answer": "Aphrodite", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938e", "question": "Who played the role of Jim Stark in the movie \"Rebel Without a Cause\"?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51215ff04d658268c92cd", "question": "Who was the first American casualty in the American Revolutionary War?", "answer": "Crispus Attucks\u00a0was the first person killed in the Boston massacre and is widely considered to be the first American casualty.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f1", "question": "Who played the lead female in the 1956 film \"Meet Me in Las Vegas\"?", "answer": "Cyd Charisse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3bec44f0f6af5b066629", "question": "What Canadian professional snooker player is nicknamed \"The Grinder\"?", "answer": "Cliff Thorburn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8da", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Limpopo river?", "answer": "Mozambique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddf166ce05a3942286dae", "question": "In which year was Tiger Woods named the PGA Tour Rookie of the Year?", "answer": "1996", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339693", "question": "Who played the role of Catwoman in the 1992 movie \"Batman Returns\"?", "answer": "Michelle Pfeiffer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ca", "question": "What bird, also known as a Man O'War, can glide for hours without flapping its wings?", "answer": "Magnificent Frigatebird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd69ffe6c0f9723ab15cb31", "question": "Which British monarch is responsible for transforming Buckingham House into a palace?", "answer": "George IV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbf", "question": "Which two public figures were assassinated in the United States in 1968?", "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr. and Robert Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c256", "question": "What is the SI physical unit of dynamic viscosity?", "answer": "Pascal-second", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339811", "question": "What film, starring Ernest Borgnine as a lonely butcher, won an Oscar for \"Best Picture\"?", "answer": "Marty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389ca", "question": "What decade was Agatha Christie's \"Murder on the Orient Express\" set in?", "answer": "The 1920s", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4de3306d333868d34d710", "question": "What name is given to Britain\u2019s policy of avoiding strict enforcement of parliamentary laws on early American colonies?", "answer": "Salutary neglect", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6008dd97f4f3bc4a292f8622", "question": "\"Operation Overlord\" was the code name for the invasion of what country during World War II?", "answer": "German-occupied France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35e", "question": "Where is the International Court of Justice?", "answer": "The Hague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4d983708b8581f80b092ae", "question": "What game won the Game of the Year award at The Game Awards 2017?", "answer": "The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec25e88dc25ca9e12ef643", "question": "Which former member of Genesis had a hit with \"One More Night\"?", "answer": "Phil Collins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e70f06d333868d34d739", "question": "What is the 6th Book of the New Testament?", "answer": "Romans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef93096ce05a3942286e8a", "question": "In what substance is Han Solo frozen in the film \"The Empire Strikes Back\"?", "answer": "Carbonite", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c6", "question": "What city is considered the waterfall capital of Canada?", "answer": "Hamilton", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c327", "question": "What type of trees yield the resin used to produce turpentine?", "answer": "Pine Trees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bbc948b60f0007efaba0e5e", "question": "What did Bob Ross specialize in doing?", "answer": "Painting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c145", "question": "What type of sport is Birling?", "answer": "Logrolling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6008e026f4f3bc4a292f862f", "question": "A parody of what song was the first to be used as a NASA wake-up call for astronauts?", "answer": "\u201cHello, Dolly!\u201d (Sent in December 1965 to the crew of Gemini 6, it was retooled \"Hello Wally\" for astronaut Wally Schirra.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133966c", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Marge's bowling ball?", "answer": "Homer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad05", "question": "Where were the 1996 Summer Olympics held?", "answer": "Atlanta, Georgia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e910b24f84e0b9f9ffc8", "question": "What year did Botswana gain its independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1966", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca4", "question": "According to his theme song, what is the most wonderful thing about Tiggers?", "answer": "I'm the only one", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d12", "question": "Whose last novel was 1961's \"The Winter of Our Discontent\"?", "answer": "John Steinbeck's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff14621b0ee8c595b6d39bf", "question": "Which classic novel's subtitle is \"The Modern Prometheus\"?", "answer": "Frankenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe51e681bf59ab7d2e380e1", "question": "Jambon is the French word for what food?", "answer": "Ham", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d4d", "question": "What popular comedian authored a book titled \"I Am America (And So Can You!)\"?", "answer": "Stephen Colbert", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ace", "question": "In the novel \"Don Quixote\", what swiveling structures are mistaken for giants?", "answer": "Windmills", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a5", "question": "Hg is the symbol for what element?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c58e", "question": "Eastern Diamondback, Massasauga and Timber are species of what animal?", "answer": "Rattlesnake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600b88741d8c1817608d53f3", "question": "From which part of a pig do we get ham?", "answer": "Hind leg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078c480eee65b76b9f2671", "question": "What was the first modern credit card?", "answer": "Diners Club", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b66c", "question": "The name of the building known as the Taj Mahal means what?", "answer": "Crown palace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfbe89dc5ec6cd98a8319", "question": "Who painted The Son of Man?", "answer": "Ren\u00e9 Magritte (The surrealist intended\u00a0the painting\u00a0of a man whose face is obscured by a hovering green apple as a self-portrait.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ccb", "question": "What nursery rhyme character \"kissed the girls and made them cry\"?", "answer": "Georgy Porgy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd5", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"canyon\"?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7cff6877e98cb97778a58", "question": "What modern city is situated near Mount Vesuvius?", "answer": "Naples", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133968c", "question": "In what town does the 1946 movie \"It's a Wonderful Life\" take place?", "answer": "Bedford Falls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6002407a4be4723ccac22165", "question": "In Tom Clancy's novel \"Patriot Games,\" what honor is bestowed on the protagonistm, Jack Ryan?", "answer": "Ryan is knighted by\u00a0Queen Elizabeth II\u00a0as an honorary\u00a0Knight Commander of the Royal Victorian Order.", "category": "arts"}]